# **Divya Jain**

Delhi, India +91 8377078364

divya.j201496@gmail.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/divyajain96

# **Summary:**

I am currently working in Barclays Bank as an Essential Banker and just completed my graduation from London, United Kingdom. I have benefitted from internship experience throughout my university in a mental health setting with Community and Housing Therapy and also have excellent customer relations' skills, having worked in the retail and food industry. I want to be an able human resource in a growth-oriented company which offers a steep learning curve, a challenging motivational carrier and ample opportunities to utilize my skills for the growth of the company.

# **Key Skills:**

- Tolerant in stressful situations.
- Non-judgmental and empathetic.
- Intercultural skills (experience studying/working overseas).
- IT skills Microsoft Office suite, & SPSS Software.
- Good communication skills Ability to communicate and interact clearly with clients and colleagues from different backgrounds.
- Social Media Planning.
- Ability to work in a flexible and disciplined way.
- Ability to work in a team.
- Capable of managing a range of tasks, prioritising to meet deadlines.
- Good interpersonal skills.
- Flair in writing.
- Public relations.
- Negotiation skills.

#### **Education:**

# 2015-2019 Middlesex University

London,

#### **United Kingdom**

• BSc Psychology with counseling skills (2:1)

#### 2013- 2015 Green Fields School

Delhi,

#### India

• H.S.C (84%) -A level Equivalent

#### 2011- 2013 Green Fields School

Delhi,

#### India

• S.S.C (CGPA. 7) -GCSE

### **Certification:**

Diploma in Child Psychology: British Learning UK

Diploma in School Management and Administration: British Learning UK

# **Relevant Experience:**

- Barclays bank, Noida, India, Personal Banker, January 2020-Present
  - Aim to provide expert, quality knowledge to the customers.
  - Taking the ownership of all the inquiries as being a front-line and first point of contact for banking requirements.
  - Educating the customers about the different communication modes and benefits and features of the proposition.
  - Capture customers response and manage accounts.
  - Assisting customer with decision-making and solutions.
  - Build a repetition with the clients in relation to the company.
  - Talking to vulnerable customers and helping them managing their finances.
  - Have dealt with different businesses within Barclays to Support such as Retail Telephony, Chats, US Collections, UK Unsecured Loans.

#### BP Industry, Greater Noida, India, Client Relationship, September 2018 -November 2019

- Aim was to work and deal with clients to guide them with company products.
- Build the bridge between the people and the company.
- Market the products and offers on different social media platforms.
- Prepare a record about the clients interactions.
- Communicating with clients through different channels.
- Providing feedback on the planning of customer service.
- Ensuring client satisfaction by providing good service.

# **Experience:**

- Management trainee, DigiVersal, Noida, India, November 2019- January 2020
  - Aim was to work with clients and help them with projects and research.
  - Provide Plagiarism free, High Quality content in academic writing.
  - Ensure client satisfaction from beginning till the end by having active communication.
  - Conducting research in depth to meet all the client requirements.
  - Comply with deadlines for every project.
  - Providing support to the team during their absence and involving in other responsibilities.

### Research Assistant, London, Placement, September 2017 - May 2019

- Aim was to work with Lecturers and do the respective research in developmental psychology (fear survey schedule for children, and Childhood fears and, sleep and fear learning in children) and Research Methods (Dancing Statistics).
- Talk to the schools to ask them to take part in the study.
- Collect data and fill in SPSS.

- Search for literature papers.
- Write literature reviews for Fear Survey Schedule, sleep and fear learning in children.
- Filled the ethics application form for the respective studies after review was ready.
- Make lists in Excel sheet such as lists of schools in the United Kingdom, Wales and Scotland, list of artists such as Virtual artists, dancers, Sculptures etc near university.

### Community and Housing Therapy, London, Student Intern, May 2016 -June 2016

- Aim was to work with residents to build therapeutic relationships that will enable the CHT team to assist with promoting recovery and interdependence.
- Talk to the residence in-group meetings.
- Take part in the activities with residents engaging them in everyday living activities in-group and individual psychotherapy.
- Recording thoughts before and after the group therapies/ activities.
- Recording in a booklet how the residents are responding to different situations.

### **Additional Experience:**

- Hollister Co., London, United Kingdom, Stock Associate, June 2016-April 2017
  - Maintaining the standard of the products and flow of merchandise
  - Providing excellent customer service
  - Suggesting product purchases for customers
  - Assisting with unloading and unpacking deliveries

### McDonalds, London, United Kingdom, Team Member, January 2016 -March 2016

- Managing the till and cash-handling
- Up selling on food and beverages
- Providing excellent customer service

# **Personal Interests:**

- Gaining more knowledge on counseling through communication and interacting with people.
- Hobbies: Playing volleyball and badminton, watching series and movies.
- Travelling to enhance cultural awareness, I have travelled across Asia (Dubai, Singapore, Malaysia, Nepal and China), United Kingdom (London, Brighton, Lake District, Glasgow, Edinburgh, Stirling, Bournemouth and Birmingham), Europe (Netherland, Germany and Hungary) and parts of India (Goa, Sikkim, Himachal Pradesh, Maharashtra, Rajasthan, Haryana, Uttar Pradesh, Delhi and Leh-Ladakh).

References are available on request